<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Need a drink? on Cocktails collected by Daniel Mentiplay</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/</link><description>Recent content in Need a drink? on Cocktails collected by Daniel Mentiplay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022-2024, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About this website</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/about/</guid><description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Daniel Mentiplay. I love making cocktails. This is where I keep my collection of cocktail recipes to share with family, friends, and others.
Note that for cocktail recipes I prefer a slightly drier drink than seems to be common (adjust according to your taste), and I use rich sugar syrup which is 2:1 sugar-to-water by volume, as opposed to simple syrup which is 1:1.
Here is a list of bartenders and cocktail guides:</description></item><item><title>Americano</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/americano/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/americano/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml Campari 45 ml sweet vermouth 45 ml soda water 1/2 orange slice Instructions Build in rocks glass over ice. Garnish with orange slice.</description></item><item><title>Artist's special</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/artists-special/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/artists-special/</guid><description>Ingredients 30 ml Scotch 30 ml Oloroso sherry 15 ml lemon juice 15 ml grenadine or redcurrant or raspberry syrup lemon twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Aviation</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/aviation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/aviation/</guid><description>Ingredients 50 ml gin 20 ml lemon juice 10 ml Maraschino liqueur 5 ml sugar syrup 5ml crème de violette cherry Instructions Shake ingredients (crème de violette optional). Serve in cocktail glass. Garnish with cherry.</description></item><item><title>Between the sheets</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/between-the-sheets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/between-the-sheets/</guid><description>Ingredients 30 ml brandy 30 ml rum 30 ml triple sec 20 ml lemon juice orange twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with orange twist.</description></item><item><title>Blood and sand</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/blood-and-sand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/blood-and-sand/</guid><description>Ingredients 20 ml Scotch 20 ml blood orange juice 20 ml sweet vermouth 20 ml cherry liqueur orange zest cherry Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a flamed orange zest and cherry.</description></item><item><title>Bloody Mary</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/bloody-mary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/bloody-mary/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml vodka 90 ml tomato juice 15 ml lemon juice 2 dashes Worcestershire sauce 2 dashes hot sauce pinch celery salt pinch pepper celery stalk lemon wedge Instructions Build in highball glass over ice. Garnish with celery and lemon.</description></item><item><title>Boulevardier</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/boulevardier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/boulevardier/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml bourbon or rye whisky 15 ml Campari 15 ml sweet vermouth orange twist Instructions Stir ingredients. Serve in rocks glass on ice. Garnish with orange twist.</description></item><item><title>Brandy crusta</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/brandy-crusta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/brandy-crusta/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml brandy 15 ml triple sec 15 ml lemon juice 10 ml Maraschino liqueur 4 dashes aromatic bitters sugar lemon twist Instructions Sugar rim a cocktail glass. Shake ingredients (Maraschino optional). Serve in cocktail glass. Garnish with long lemon twist lining the inside of the glass.</description></item><item><title>Brooklyn</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/brooklyn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/brooklyn/</guid><description>Ingredients 50 ml rye whisky 20 ml dry vermouth 7.5 ml amaro 5 ml Maraschino liqueur orange twist Instructions Stir ingredients. Serve up. Garnish with orange twist.</description></item><item><title>Caipirinha</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/caipirinha/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/caipirinha/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml cachaça 1/2 lime 15 ml sugar syrup Instructions Muddle quartered lime and syrup in a rocks glass. Add ice and cachaça and stir.</description></item><item><title>Corpse reviver no. 2</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/corpse-reviver-no.-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/corpse-reviver-no.-2/</guid><description>Ingredients 20 ml gin 20 ml triple sec 20 ml Lillet Blanc 20 ml lemon juice 4 dashes absinthe cherry Instructions (Optional) rinse glass with absinthe. Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a cherry.</description></item><item><title>Cosmopolitan</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/cosmopolitan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/cosmopolitan/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml vodka (citron) 30 ml triple sec 30 ml lime juice 15 ml cranberry juice lemon twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Cube libre</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/cube-libre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/cube-libre/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rum 90 ml cola 5 ml lime juice lime wedge Instructions Build in highball glass over ice. Garnish with a lime wedge.</description></item><item><title>Daiquiri</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/daiquiri/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/daiquiri/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rum 20 ml lime juice 10 ml sugar syrup lime zest lime slice Instructions Shake ingredients including lime zest. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a lime slice.</description></item><item><title>Dark 'n' stormy</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/dark-n-stormy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/dark-n-stormy/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rum 90 ml ginger beer lime wedge Instructions Build in highball glass over ice. Garnish with a lime wedge.</description></item><item><title>Gin and tonic</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/gin-and-tonic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/gin-and-tonic/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml gin 90 ml tonic water lime or lemon wedge Instructions Build in highball glass over ice. Garnish with lime or lemon wedge.</description></item><item><title>Hemingway special</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/hemingway-special/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/hemingway-special/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rum 30 ml grapefruit juice 15 ml lime juice 15 ml Maraschino liqueur 5 ml sugar syrup lime slice Instructions Shake with ice. Serve in a cocktail glass Garnish with lime slice.</description></item><item><title>Jasmine</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/jasmine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/jasmine/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml gin 30 ml triple sec 20 ml Campari 15 ml lemon juice lemon twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Manhattan</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/manhattan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/manhattan/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rye whisky or bourbon 20 ml sweet vermouth 4 dashes aromatic bitters cherry Instructions Stir ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a cherry.</description></item><item><title>Margarita</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/margarita/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/margarita/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml tequila 30 ml lime juice 15 ml triple sec lime slice Instructions Shake ingredients Serve in cocktail glass (rimmed with salt). Garnish with a lime slice.</description></item><item><title>Martinez</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martinez/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martinez/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml gin 45 ml sweet vermouth 5 ml Maraschino liqueur 4 dashes aromatic bitters lemon twist Instructions Stirred over ice. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Martini</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martini/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martini/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml gin 20 ml dry vermouth 4 dashes orange bitters lemon twist olives Instructions Stir ingredients (orange bitters are optional). Make sure the drink and glass are cold. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a lemon twist or olives.</description></item><item><title>Mojito</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/mojito/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/mojito/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rum 20 ml lime juice 20 ml sugar syrup a few mint leaves soda water mint sprig Instructions Crush ice in clean tea towel. Lightly clap mint. Add ingredients except soda to highball glass. Add crushed ice and stir briefly, and top with soda water. Garnish with a mint sprig.</description></item><item><title>Negroni</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/negroni/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/negroni/</guid><description>Ingredients 30 ml gin 30 ml Campari 45 ml sweet vermouth 1/2 slice orange Instructions Stir ingredients. Serve in rocks glass over ice. Garnish with orange slice.</description></item><item><title>Old fashioned</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/old-fashioned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/old-fashioned/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rye whisky or bourbon 5 ml sugar syrup 4 dashes aromatic bitters orange or lemon twist Instructions Stir ingredients. Serve in a rocks glass over ice. Garnish with a twist.</description></item><item><title>Paloma</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/paloma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/paloma/</guid><description>Note: There are two recipes, a &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; one and a &amp;ldquo;complex&amp;rdquo; one.
Ingredients (simple) 60 ml tequila 120 ml grapefruit soda 5 ml lime juice pinch of salt Instructions (simple) Mix together in a highball glass over ice. Garnish with lime wedge. Ingredients (complex) 45 ml tequila 30 ml grapefruit juice 15 ml lime juice 5 ml agave syrup splash of soda water (optional) lime or grapefruit wedge Instructions (complex) Shake ingredients.</description></item><item><title>Paper plane</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/paper-plane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/paper-plane/</guid><description>Ingredients 20ml bourbon 20ml Aperol 20ml Amaro Nonino or Montenegro 20ml lemon juice lemon twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist (or miniature paper plane).</description></item><item><title>Pisco sour</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/pisco-sour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/pisco-sour/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml pisco 30 ml lime juice 15 ml sugar syrup 1/2 egg white aromatic bitters lime slice Instructions Dry shake ingredients. Then shake with ice. Serve in a rocks glass without ice. Garnish with drops of bitters and a lime slice.</description></item><item><title>Piña colada</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/pi%C3%B1a-colada/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/pi%C3%B1a-colada/</guid><description>Ingredients 30 ml rum 30 ml coconut milk 90 ml pineapple juice pineapple slice cherry Instructions Build in cocktail glass over ice. Garnish with pineapple and cherry.</description></item><item><title>Saratoga</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/saratoga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/saratoga/</guid><description>Ingredients 30 ml brandy 30 ml rye whisky or bourbon 30 ml sweet vermouth 2 dashes aromatic bitters orange twist Instructions Stir ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a twist.</description></item><item><title>Sazerac</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/sazerac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/sazerac/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rye whisky 5 ml sugar syrup 4 dashes Peychaud&amp;rsquo;s Bitters 4 dashes absinthe lemon twist Instructions (Optional) rinse glass with absinthe. Stirred. Serve in a rocks glass without ice. Garnish with a lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Scofflaw</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/scofflaw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/scofflaw/</guid><description>Ingredients 50 ml rye whisky 25 ml dry vermouth 10 ml grenadine 4 dashes orange bitters 15 ml lemon juice lemon twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Scotch and soda</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/scotch-and-soda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/scotch-and-soda/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml Scotch 90 ml soda water Instructions Build in rocks glass over ice.</description></item><item><title>Sidecar</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/sidecar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/sidecar/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml brandy 30 ml triple sec 15 ml lemon juice orange twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with an orange twist.</description></item><item><title>Southside</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/southside/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/southside/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml gin 30 ml lime juice 15 ml sugar syrup 1 mint sprig 1 mint leaf Instructions Shaken (without mint). Rolled (with mint). Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with mint leaf.</description></item><item><title>Spritz Veneziano</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/spritz-veneziano/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/spritz-veneziano/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml prosecco 45 ml Aperol 20 ml soda water orange slice olive Instructions Build in wine glass over ice. Garnish with orange slice and olive.</description></item><item><title>Tom Collins</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/tom-collins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/tom-collins/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml gin 30 ml lemon juice 15 ml sugar syrup soda water lemon slice Instructions Add ingredients except soda to highball glass and stir to combine. Add soda water to halfway up glass. Fill glass with ice. Garnish with lemon slice.</description></item><item><title>Tommy's margarita</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/tommys-margarita/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/tommys-margarita/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml tequila 30 ml lime juice 15 ml agave syrup lime slice Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a rocks glass over ice. Garnish with a lime slice.</description></item><item><title>Whiskey sour</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/whiskey-sour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/whiskey-sour/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml bourbon 30 ml lemon juice 15 ml sugar syrup 4 dashes orange bitters 1/2 egg white (optional) cherry orange twist Instructions Dry shake ingredients. Then shake with ice and double strain. Serve in a rocks glass over fresh ice. Garnish with orange twist and cherry.</description></item><item><title>White lady</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/white-lady/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/white-lady/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml gin 30 ml triple sec 20 ml lemon juice lemon twist Instructions Shake over ice. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item></channel></rss>