<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bitters on Cocktails collected by Daniel Mentiplay</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/alcohol/bitters/</link><description>Recent content in bitters on Cocktails collected by Daniel Mentiplay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022-2024, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/alcohol/bitters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brandy crusta</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/brandy-crusta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/brandy-crusta/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml brandy 15 ml triple sec 15 ml lemon juice 10 ml Maraschino liqueur 4 dashes aromatic bitters sugar lemon twist Instructions Sugar rim a cocktail glass. Shake ingredients (Maraschino optional). Serve in cocktail glass. Garnish with long lemon twist lining the inside of the glass.</description></item><item><title>Manhattan</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/manhattan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/manhattan/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rye whisky or bourbon 20 ml sweet vermouth 4 dashes aromatic bitters cherry Instructions Stir ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a cherry.</description></item><item><title>Martinez</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martinez/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martinez/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml gin 45 ml sweet vermouth 5 ml Maraschino liqueur 4 dashes aromatic bitters lemon twist Instructions Stirred over ice. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Martini</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martini/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martini/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml gin 20 ml dry vermouth 4 dashes orange bitters lemon twist olives Instructions Stir ingredients (orange bitters are optional). Make sure the drink and glass are cold. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a lemon twist or olives.</description></item><item><title>Old fashioned</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/old-fashioned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/old-fashioned/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rye whisky or bourbon 5 ml sugar syrup 4 dashes aromatic bitters orange or lemon twist Instructions Stir ingredients. Serve in a rocks glass over ice. Garnish with a twist.</description></item><item><title>Saratoga</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/saratoga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/saratoga/</guid><description>Ingredients 30 ml brandy 30 ml rye whisky or bourbon 30 ml sweet vermouth 2 dashes aromatic bitters orange twist Instructions Stir ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a twist.</description></item><item><title>Sazerac</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/sazerac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/sazerac/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rye whisky 5 ml sugar syrup 4 dashes creole bitters 4 dashes absinthe lemon twist Instructions (Optional) rinse glass with absinthe. Stirred. Serve in a rocks glass without ice. Garnish with a lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Scofflaw</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/scofflaw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/scofflaw/</guid><description>Ingredients 50 ml rye whisky 25 ml dry vermouth 10 ml grenadine 4 dashes orange bitters 15 ml lemon juice lemon twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Vieux Carré</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/vieux-carr%C3%A9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/vieux-carr%C3%A9/</guid><description>Ingredients 22.5 ml rye whiskey 22.5 ml brandy 22.5 ml sweet vermouth 10 ml Bénédictine liqueur 2 dashes creole bitters 2 dash aromatic bitters lemon twist Instructions Stirred. Serve in a rocks glass without ice. Garnish with a lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Whiskey sour</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/whiskey-sour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/whiskey-sour/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml bourbon 30 ml lemon juice 15 ml sugar syrup 4 dashes orange bitters 1/2 egg white (optional) cherry orange twist Instructions Dry shake ingredients. Then shake with ice and double strain. Serve in a rocks glass over fresh ice. Garnish with orange twist and cherry.</description></item></channel></rss>