<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lime juice on Cocktails collected by Daniel Mentiplay</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/mixers/lime-juice/</link><description>Recent content in lime juice on Cocktails collected by Daniel Mentiplay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022-2024, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/mixers/lime-juice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caipirinha</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/caipirinha/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/caipirinha/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml cachaça 1/2 lime 15 ml sugar syrup Instructions Muddle quartered lime and syrup in a rocks glass. Add ice and cachaça and stir.</description></item><item><title>Cosmopolitan</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/cosmopolitan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/cosmopolitan/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml vodka (citron) 30 ml triple sec 30 ml lime juice 15 ml cranberry juice lemon twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Cube libre</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/cube-libre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/cube-libre/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rum 90 ml cola 5 ml lime juice lime wedge Instructions Build in highball glass over ice. Garnish with a lime wedge.</description></item><item><title>Daiquiri</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/daiquiri/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/daiquiri/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rum 20 ml lime juice 10 ml sugar syrup lime zest lime slice Instructions Shake ingredients including lime zest. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a lime slice.</description></item><item><title>Hemingway special</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/hemingway-special/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/hemingway-special/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rum 30 ml grapefruit juice 15 ml lime juice 15 ml Maraschino liqueur 5 ml sugar syrup lime slice Instructions Shake with ice. Serve in a cocktail glass Garnish with lime slice.</description></item><item><title>Margarita</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/margarita/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/margarita/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml tequila 30 ml lime juice 15 ml triple sec lime slice Instructions Shake ingredients Serve in cocktail glass (rimmed with salt). Garnish with a lime slice.</description></item><item><title>Mojito</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/mojito/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/mojito/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rum 20 ml lime juice 20 ml sugar syrup a few mint leaves soda water mint sprig Instructions Crush ice in clean tea towel. Lightly clap mint. Add ingredients except soda to highball glass. Add crushed ice and stir briefly, and top with soda water. Garnish with a mint sprig.</description></item><item><title>Paloma</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/paloma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/paloma/</guid><description>Note: There are two recipes, a &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; one and a &amp;ldquo;complex&amp;rdquo; one.
Ingredients (simple) 60 ml tequila 120 ml grapefruit soda 5 ml lime juice pinch of salt Instructions (simple) Mix together in a highball glass over ice. Garnish with lime wedge. Ingredients (complex) 45 ml tequila 30 ml grapefruit juice 15 ml lime juice 5 ml agave syrup splash of soda water (optional) lime or grapefruit wedge Instructions (complex) Shake ingredients.</description></item><item><title>Pisco sour</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/pisco-sour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/pisco-sour/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml pisco 30 ml lime juice 15 ml sugar syrup 1/2 egg white aromatic bitters lime slice Instructions Dry shake ingredients. Then shake with ice. Serve in a rocks glass without ice. Garnish with drops of bitters and a lime slice.</description></item><item><title>Southside</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/southside/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/southside/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml gin 30 ml lime juice 15 ml sugar syrup 1 mint sprig 1 mint leaf Instructions Shaken (without mint). Rolled (with mint). Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with mint leaf.</description></item><item><title>Tommy's margarita</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/tommys-margarita/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/tommys-margarita/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml tequila 30 ml lime juice 15 ml agave syrup lime slice Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a rocks glass over ice. Garnish with a lime slice.</description></item></channel></rss>