<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lemon juice on Cocktails collected by Daniel Mentiplay</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/mixers/lemon-juice/</link><description>Recent content in lemon juice on Cocktails collected by Daniel Mentiplay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/mixers/lemon-juice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Artist's special</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/artists-special/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/artists-special/</guid><description>Ingredients 30 ml Scotch 30 ml Oloroso sherry 15 ml lemon juice 15 ml grenadine or redcurrant or raspberry syrup lemon twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Aviation</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/aviation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/aviation/</guid><description>Ingredients 50 ml gin 20 ml lemon juice 10 ml Maraschino liqueur 5 ml sugar syrup 5ml crème de violette cherry Instructions Shake ingredients (crème de violette optional). Serve in cocktail glass. Garnish with cherry.</description></item><item><title>Between the sheets</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/between-the-sheets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/between-the-sheets/</guid><description>Ingredients 30 ml brandy 30 ml rum 30 ml triple sec 20 ml lemon juice orange twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with orange twist.</description></item><item><title>Bloody Mary</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/bloody-mary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/bloody-mary/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml vodka 90 ml tomato juice 15 ml lemon juice 2 dashes Worcestershire sauce 2 dashes hot sauce pinch celery salt pinch pepper celery stalk lemon wedge Instructions Build in highball glass over ice. Garnish with celery and lemon.</description></item><item><title>Brandy crusta</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/brandy-crusta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/brandy-crusta/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml brandy 15 ml triple sec 15 ml lemon juice 10 ml Maraschino liqueur 4 dashes aromatic bitters sugar lemon twist Instructions Sugar rim a cocktail glass. Shake ingredients (Maraschino optional). Serve in cocktail glass. Garnish with long lemon twist lining the inside of the glass.</description></item><item><title>Corpse reviver no. 2</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/corpse-reviver-no.-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/corpse-reviver-no.-2/</guid><description>Ingredients 20 ml gin 20 ml triple sec 20 ml Lillet Blanc 20 ml lemon juice 4 dashes absinthe cherry Instructions (Optional) rinse glass with absinthe. Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a cherry.</description></item><item><title>Jasmine</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/jasmine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/jasmine/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml gin 30 ml triple sec 20 ml Campari 15 ml lemon juice lemon twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Paper plane</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/paper-plane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/paper-plane/</guid><description>Ingredients 20ml bourbon 20ml Aperol 20ml Amaro Nonino or Montenegro 20ml lemon juice lemon twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist (or miniature paper plane).</description></item><item><title>Scofflaw</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/scofflaw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/scofflaw/</guid><description>Ingredients 50 ml rye whisky 25 ml dry vermouth 10 ml grenadine 4 dashes orange bitters 15 ml lemon juice lemon twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Sidecar</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/sidecar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/sidecar/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml brandy 30 ml triple sec 15 ml lemon juice orange twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with an orange twist.</description></item><item><title>Tom Collins</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/tom-collins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/tom-collins/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml gin 30 ml lemon juice 15 ml sugar syrup soda water lemon slice Instructions Add ingredients except soda to highball glass and stir to combine. Add soda water to halfway up glass. Fill glass with ice. Garnish with lemon slice.</description></item><item><title>Whiskey sour</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/whiskey-sour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/whiskey-sour/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml bourbon 30 ml lemon juice 15 ml sugar syrup 4 dashes orange bitters 1/2 egg white (optional) cherry orange twist Instructions Dry shake ingredients. Then shake with ice and double strain. Serve in a rocks glass over fresh ice. Garnish with orange twist and cherry.</description></item><item><title>White lady</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/white-lady/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/white-lady/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml gin 30 ml triple sec 20 ml lemon juice lemon twist Instructions Shake over ice. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item></channel></rss>