<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>gin on Cocktails collected by Daniel Mentiplay</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/alcohol/gin/</link><description>Recent content in gin on Cocktails collected by Daniel Mentiplay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022-2024, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/alcohol/gin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aviation</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/aviation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/aviation/</guid><description>Ingredients 50 ml gin 20 ml lemon juice 10 ml Maraschino liqueur 5 ml sugar syrup 5ml crème de violette cherry Instructions Shake ingredients (crème de violette optional). Serve in cocktail glass. Garnish with cherry.</description></item><item><title>Corpse reviver no. 2</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/corpse-reviver-no.-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/corpse-reviver-no.-2/</guid><description>Ingredients 20 ml gin 20 ml triple sec 20 ml Lillet Blanc 20 ml lemon juice 4 dashes absinthe cherry Instructions (Optional) rinse glass with absinthe. Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a cherry.</description></item><item><title>Gin and tonic</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/gin-and-tonic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/gin-and-tonic/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml gin 90 ml tonic water lime or lemon wedge Instructions Build in highball glass over ice. Garnish with lime or lemon wedge.</description></item><item><title>Jasmine</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/jasmine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/jasmine/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml gin 30 ml triple sec 20 ml Campari 15 ml lemon juice lemon twist Instructions Shake ingredients. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Martinez</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martinez/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martinez/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml gin 45 ml sweet vermouth 5 ml Maraschino liqueur 4 dashes aromatic bitters lemon twist Instructions Stirred over ice. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item><item><title>Martini</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martini/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martini/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml gin 20 ml dry vermouth 4 dashes orange bitters lemon twist olives Instructions Stir ingredients (orange bitters are optional). Make sure the drink and glass are cold. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a lemon twist or olives.</description></item><item><title>Negroni</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/negroni/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/negroni/</guid><description>Ingredients 30 ml gin 30 ml Campari 30 ml sweet vermouth 1/2 slice orange Instructions Stir ingredients. Serve in rocks glass over ice. Garnish with orange slice.</description></item><item><title>Southside</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/southside/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/southside/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml gin 30 ml lime juice 15 ml sugar syrup 1 mint sprig 1 mint leaf Instructions Shaken (without mint). Rolled (with mint). Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with mint leaf.</description></item><item><title>Tom Collins</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/tom-collins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/tom-collins/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml gin 30 ml lemon juice 15 ml sugar syrup soda water lemon slice Instructions Add ingredients except soda to highball glass and stir to combine. Add soda water to halfway up glass. Fill glass with ice. Garnish with lemon slice.</description></item><item><title>White lady</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/white-lady/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/white-lady/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml gin 30 ml triple sec 20 ml lemon juice lemon twist Instructions Shake over ice. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item></channel></rss>