<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Maraschino liqueur on Cocktails collected by Daniel Mentiplay</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/alcohol/maraschino-liqueur/</link><description>Recent content in Maraschino liqueur on Cocktails collected by Daniel Mentiplay</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022-2024, Daniel Mentiplay.</copyright><atom:link href="https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/alcohol/maraschino-liqueur/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aviation</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/aviation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/aviation/</guid><description>Ingredients 50 ml gin 20 ml lemon juice 10 ml Maraschino liqueur 5 ml sugar syrup 5ml crème de violette cherry Instructions Shake ingredients (crème de violette optional). Serve in cocktail glass. Garnish with cherry.</description></item><item><title>Brandy crusta</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/brandy-crusta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/brandy-crusta/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml brandy 15 ml triple sec 15 ml lemon juice 10 ml Maraschino liqueur 4 dashes aromatic bitters sugar lemon twist Instructions Sugar rim a cocktail glass. Shake ingredients (Maraschino optional). Serve in cocktail glass. Garnish with long lemon twist lining the inside of the glass.</description></item><item><title>Brooklyn</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/brooklyn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/brooklyn/</guid><description>Ingredients 50 ml rye whisky 20 ml dry vermouth 7.5 ml amaro 5 ml Maraschino liqueur orange twist Instructions Stir ingredients. Serve up. Garnish with orange twist.</description></item><item><title>Hemingway special</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/hemingway-special/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/hemingway-special/</guid><description>Ingredients 60 ml rum 30 ml grapefruit juice 15 ml lime juice 15 ml Maraschino liqueur 5 ml sugar syrup lime slice Instructions Shake with ice. Serve in a cocktail glass Garnish with lime slice.</description></item><item><title>Martinez</title><link>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martinez/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cocktails.danielmentiplay.com/martinez/</guid><description>Ingredients 45 ml gin 45 ml sweet vermouth 5 ml Maraschino liqueur 4 dashes aromatic bitters lemon twist Instructions Stirred over ice. Serve in a cocktail glass. Garnish with lemon twist.</description></item></channel></rss>